thekennelclub.org.uk 2016-10-12

# Privacy policy • The Kennel Club

**Registered owner**

This website is owned and maintained by:

The Kennel Club Limited

Registered in England and Wales

Registration number 8217778

Registered office:

1-5 Clarges Street

Piccadilly

London

W1J 8AB

**Privacy statement**

This policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

Use of this website by you constitutes acceptance by you of this privacy policy (" **Privacy Policy"** ). If you do not wish to accept this Privacy Policy, then you must not use this website.

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is:

  * to assure you that we recognise and fully respect the privacy and personal data of the visitors to this website; and
  * to explain what personal information we collect from this website and how we ensure its best protection.

This Privacy Policy governs this website at [www.thekennelclub.org.uk](http://www.thekennelclub.org.uk/) (referred to in this Privacy Policy as the " **Website"** ). Other sites to which the Website may be linked are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

**Data protection**

The Kennel Club complies with the Data Protection Act 1998 ("the **DPA"** ). For the purposes of the DPA, The Kennel Club is the data controller and sole owner of the personal data collected on the Website.

The Kennel Club does not sell, share or transfer this information except as set out in this Privacy Policy.

We use up-to-date industry procedures to keep personal data as safe and secure as possible and to protect against loss, unauthorised disclosure or access. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

The DPA gives you the right to access details that we hold about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the DPA. A small fee may be payable in respect of any access request.

For more information please refer to our Data Protection Policy.

**Information we may collect from you**

It is not necessary for you to register with us in order to access the Website. However we may collect some information from interactive features such as online surveys, contact and registration forms. The basic personal information about you which we may collect and process is:

  * your name
  * your user type (e.g. breeder, owner, judge etc)
  * your e-mail address
  * your user ID and password.

Depending on what you are registering for, additional information may be collected from you.

We may also collect and process information provided by you at the time of posting material to the Website, as well as details of your visit to the Website (including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data), and the resources that you use. Further, if you contact us, we may also keep a record of that correspondence.

**Uses made of the information**

We may use information held about you in the following ways:

  * to ensure that content from the Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer
  * to provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so, and
  * to notify you about changes to our service.

We may also use your data for the purposes of advertising, marketing and public relations, so as to provide you with information about relevant goods and services which may be of interest to you and we may contact you about these by post or telephone.

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, please email the [Web Team](mailto:webteam@thekennelclub.org.uk)

**Cookies**

Please see our separate page on cookies.

**Changing the information we hold about you**

If you would like to change any information we hold about you that has been collected via use of this Website or want to it to be removed from our database, you should contact the [Web Team](mailto:webteam@thekennelclub.org.uk).

**Third Parties**

We do not at present forward the information collected about you to any third parties except where required by law to do so or in order to enforce or apply our Conditions of use. However, we reserve the right to change this position at any time.

If the Kennel Club chooses to employ the services of a third party it will inform you, but the change will only apply in relation to information which we collect from you after we have informed you of the change. We will not disclose any information we have already collected about you without your consent, other than where required to do so by law or in order to enforce or apply our Conditions of use.

At all times, the Kennel Club will control and be responsible for the use of your personal information.

**Consent**

By using the Website, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information in the manner set out above.

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing at any time by contacting the [Web Team](mailto:webteam@thekennelclub.org.uk).

The Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

The internet and data privacy best practice are both developing. We therefore reserve the right to revise this Privacy Policy at any time. If this Privacy Policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to the [Web Team](mailto:webteam@thekennelclub.org.uk).
